[Episode 30]
- Cheers.
- Alright.
Meng, do you remember our promise?
We promised
that if we couldn't find the right person,
I would open a restaurant,
and you would teach at the Women's Academy.
When we got old, we would
keep each other company and not be lonely.
Unexpectedly, you're going to get married.
It seems we're so blessed.
Zhi Li has Nian.
I have His Majesty,
and you have Mr. Shen.
Let's have another drink.
Cheers!
Meng,
ever since we came back from the hot spring,
you've been acting strange.
Is something on your mind?
Would she ever keep anything from you?
She must be worried about tomorrow's wedding.
To wear the crown, one must bear its weight.
Being an empress
is not as carefree as being an official
at the Censorate.
Don't worry.
No matter how heavy the crown is,
we will all support you.
That's right.
His Majesty protects you in the court.
Zhi Shu and Nian guard you in the palace,
and Fu Zhi and I are around you.
And Yin Qing makes you laugh.
The entire Censorate
will always have your back.
Come on.
Cheers!
I'm just afraid this is all but a dream,
and when I wake up, everything will be gone.
Meng,
if you ever feel unhappy in the palace,
just come back to Bofeng House.
This will always be a home for you.
I will always shield you.
I don't wish you prosperity.
I only wish you happiness and health.
Meng, whether you are Director Meng
or the empress,
in my heart,
you will always be my best friend
who guided my growth
and protected me in every way.
You will forever be the girl
I am proud of and admire most.
Alright, tomorrow is your wedding day,
so cheer up!
Come on.
Here is to our empress.
And to the night of drinking like this.
Your Highness, by this time tomorrow,
all the lanterns in the capital will
be replaced with white mourning banners.
The eight-year blood debt shall be repaid.
In the Battle of Humen Pass back then,
Ying Gua, as the Crown Prince,
shot an arrow through my uncle's throat,
ruining the fortunes of my mother's clan.
Since then, my father
has been paying attention to my brother only.
Who does he think he is?
He is just a coward hiding in the royal tent
and playing political games.
Your Highness, the time for revenge has come.
Xu Ting firmly believes
Your Highness has come to offer warhorses
and promote a marriage alliance.
[Imperial Permit to the Capital]
I've obtained the city-opening token.
Just wait for the signal tomorrow,
and our assassination squad
will head straight for the capital.
Yes.
Your Highness,
sorry to have kept you waiting.
Mr. Shangguan,
you actually approached me so quietly
that even our Wind Listeners
couldn't detect your presence.
Very impressive!
I'm flattered.
To remind you,
what you should care about
is tomorrow's operation.
During the wedding tomorrow,
the escort procession must pass
through Changle Street from the Censorate.
We've turned the leader of the escort guards.
At that time, he will use the pretext
of searching for assassins
to divert half of the Imperial Guards.
There are crisscrossing lanes there,
and Ying Gua will die there.
Mr. Shangguan,
are you sure your ambush is foolproof?
Ying Gua is as cunning as a fox.
Back then, with 3,000 light cavalrymen,
he lured my 30,000 troops into a death trap.
If this is a setup again,
you and I will be trapped.
Since I work from the inside with you,
you can rest assured.
Your Highness,
you'll lead your troops to fight head-on
while my men already lie in ambush,
responsible for contacting the princess.
Even if Ying Gua makes a perfect plan,
his wedding feast will be his last meal.
Interesting.
Though we have worked until now,
I have yet to see your true face.
When Zhongwan is restored,
my face, hidden for ten years,
will naturally be shown.
At that time, I'll drink with you
to honor Ying Gua's death.
The hour of You has passed.
Ying Gua is about to die.
The Ning Empire should also come to an end.
This time,
I'll personally cut off Ying Gua's head.
This is the grand wedding
of the emperor and empress.
Today, betrothal gifts are prepared
to display the emperor's sincerity
and to honor the empress's virtue.
The gifts include
ten bolts of high-quality silk brocade,
a pair of blue jade nuptial cups,
a pair of kingfisher feather vases,
one black pearl,
one jade scepter,
and a set of golden phoenix hairpins,
symbolizing happiness.
Will I still be able to see you often?
Your Majesty.
Of course, I will always be your Meng.
We promised not to cry today.
We must happily see Meng off.
The auspicious hour is approaching.
We respectfully welcome Her Majesty.
I never thought the story in the storybooks
would actually come true.
Shun, go buy me some text books.
Why, madam?
I'll also take the imperial exam
and become a scholar next year.
Your Highness,
the carriage has reached the street corner.
Look, how grand!
Prepare to die, Ying Gua!
Run!
Did you think killing me
would end everything?
Return to the Sacred Ancestral Hall
to protect His Majesty!
The auspicious hour has arrived.
Welcome the emperor and empress
into the hall to announce the ancestors.
Please offer incense.
First bow to the ancestors
who expanded the land.
Yao.
Second bow
for the eternal stability of the land.
Third bow for your lifelong commitment.
Yao, kill him.
Concluded.
Yao, he is the enemy
who destroyed your country.
Kill him, Yao.
He is the enemy who destroyed your country.
Kill him.
Yao, kill him.
Your Majesty!
Guards! Protect His Majesty!
Meng, what's wrong with you?
Back off, you lot!
Otherwise, your emperor will die!
Stop playing tricks!
Who exactly are you?
How dare you assassinate His Majesty here!
Over ten years ago,
you killed 100,000 people in my country.
Did you
forget your blood debt?
Zhongwan remnants!
You destroyed my country,
yet call us remnants.
Today, I will use the blood of your emperor
to rest the souls of my people.
I'll kill you!
Yin Qing? How could it be you?
After hiding for so long,
you finally show yourself today.
Do you really think this is a place
you can come and go as you please?
Meng, you already knew about this?
Yin Qing,
I already replaced your incense
three days ago.
Today, I used myself as bait to set this trap
to lure all of you out.
Do you know how long
I have waited for this moment?
You actually worked with him to set us up!
Your Majesty,
the nine gates of the Sacred Ancestral Hall
have been sealed.
Today, they cannot escape.
The Second Prince of Beijian
and his men have been annihilated.
The Blood Moon Society
no longer has any support.
What exactly happened?
Lord Xu,
you secretly issued a tributary credential,
helping the Second Prince of Beijian
work with the Blood Moon Society
and lead troops to infiltrate the capital.
Your Majesty, allow me to explain.
I must have fallen for a trap
to have signed that credential.
Your Majesty, the priority is
to exterminate the Zhongwan remnants!
Ying Gua,
since I came here today,
I never planned to leave alive.
Seize them!
Yin Qing, stop now.
- Don't do anything you'll regret!
- It's you who will regret!
I suffered so much
and planned every step carefully,
helping you become the most powerful person.
Today, just by killing Ying Gua,
we can restore Zhongwan.
It will only make countless people homeless.
I prefer to give up the blood feud then.
Besides,
I am now a member of the Ning Empire.
Director Meng is actually
in league with the Blood Moon Society?
That's absolutely not true!
Seize all remnants of Blood Moon Society!
You forced me to do this!
All of you, look closely.
Do you truly want her to be your empress?
The Black Bird tattoo?
That's the mark of the Zhongwan royals!
You are the princess of Zhongwan!
A foreign princess has actually been
stirring up things in our country.
Guards! Execute her on the spot!
Who dares?
Your Majesty,
did you already know about her identity?
are you going to hand over the Ning Empire
to the Zhongwan remnants?
Meng Ting Hui previously
did not know her origins,
but I'm clear about every single thing
she did for the Ning Empire.
Drop the act, Princess.
We plotted the Eternity Pill trouble,
Gu Qin's execution,
and the failure
of the marriage alliance with Beijian.
It's all to make internal
and external conflicts here.
Did you think
that by driving her into a corner
and pinning all the disasters on her,
she would join you to restore your country?
You keep her by your side just to use her,
don't you?
There will always be 100,000 dead souls
between you two.
You can never be together.
Your Majesty, enough talking.
Quickly kill the evil woman
and the Zhongwan remnants
once and for all!
Since you say I'm an evil woman
who brings disaster to the country,
today, I will cut out my Black Bird tattoo
to show you my loyalty.
Don't!
The Black Bird tattoo is destroyed.
I am no longer a princess of Zhongwan.
I am just Meng Ting Hui.
Lord Xu!
If you want to kill our emperor,
you must step over my body first.
Lord Xu!
Lord Xu, wake up!
Get the imperial physician. Quickly!
Yes! Imperial physician!
- Your Majesty.
- Imperial physician!
Your Majesty,
I was wrong before.
Do not blame me.
I can't
serve Your Majesty anymore.
Lord Xu!
Princess, we should be happy.
I have avenged you and my sister.
Execute these remnants!
Xu Ting died, so your heart hurts?
When your troops massacred our people,
can you imagine how I felt back then?
You and I,
Zhongwan and Ning Empire,
are irreconcilable enemies.
Since our deep blood feud cannot be settled,
today, I will use your life to end it all.
Mr. Shangguan!
Your Majesty!
Meng!
Hasn't there been enough killing
between Ning Empire and Zhongwan?
Your Majesty, please spare Yin Qing's life.
I personally gave you the hairpin,
yet you actually use it to threaten me.
I know Your Majesty hates Yin Qing,
but I cannot watch him die.
I cannot watch the hatred
between the two countries grow deeper.
Lord Xu died protecting me.
If I don't kill him today,
how can I guard the land
and protect the people?
Today, he must die!
Stop!
I am protecting Yin Qing
for the sake of Ning Empire as well.
Your Majesty, do not listen to Meng Ting Hui!
You absolutely must not let them go.
I implore Your Majesty
to execute her and her followers
for the sake of national stability.
Your Majesty,
sparing them is a recipe for disaster.
Today, we mustn't let them leave alive.
Nian, do you have to be so ruthless?
Your Majesty, these people survived back then
and stirred up trouble.
You must not let it happen again.
Zhi Shu,
you know Meng won't hurt His Majesty.
- I beg you--
- We implore Your Majesty
to execute the princess and her followers
for the sake of national stability!
The phoenix pendant is broken,
and you and I are over.
I'll never yield a single inch of my land.
Let them go.
Your Majesty!
The throne shook.
The evil woman escaped.
The loyal minister died.
The border defense collapsed.
An infatuated emperor
destroys the land.
The throne shook.
The evil woman escaped.
The loyal minister died.
The border defense collapsed.
[Chunman House]
[Bofeng House]
Ms. Yan,
will Miss Meng restore her country
and attack us?
- Ms. Yan.
- Madam!
Terrible news! There's going to be a war!
My relatives at the border say
they've seen enemy troops.
Then we should quickly stock up on food.
If a war really breaks out,
food will be lifesaving.
Yes, you're right.
Your Majesty.
No need for formalities.
Please take a seat.
You must have already heard
that they call me a fatuous ruler.
In my view,
Your Majesty is using the land
as a chessboard,
and benevolence as bait.
This is great wisdom.
I heard from Zhi Shu
that Your Majesty will issue a new policy
for Zhongwan.
All who surrender will not be slaves anymore,
have fertile land,
and be allowed to become officials
through the Imperial Exams.
It's to show our sincerity
to the Zhongwan remnants.
I will bear the infamy,
but the game must be played by my rules.
Your Majesty,
are you going to the battlefield?
Now, with both chancellor positions vacant,
the court is in turmoil.
Moreover, Beijian has vicious ambitions,
colluding with Zhongwan remnants
to assassinate Your Majesty.
You will be in grave danger.
You can't leave the capital.
I invited you over
precisely to ask you to oversee the court,
command the six ministries,
and stabilize the government.
That day, I let Yin Qing go,
but it was not for Meng Ting Hui.
Yin Qing is the leader
of the Zhongwan remnants.
If I killed him on the spot,
it would incite the hatred of the remnants,
and then we would face a joint attack
from Zhongwan and Beijian.
The war with Beijian is inevitable,
so we might as well strike first.
Moreover, that day,
Meng Ting Hui also risked her life.
She was betting
that I could find a third path,
a path different from how my father
handled the clashes between two countries.
When you taught me how to rule over the land,
you said the true ruler
should be magnanimous.
I wish to unify this fractured land
and bring people peace and prosperity.
So, will you help me play this game?
I once said
the land is the chessboard,
and the ruler is the player.
I am willing to play this chess game
for Your Majesty.
I have retired for ten years.
I truly never expected
that I could still serve Your Majesty
and the country.
With your support,
I can campaign without worries.
From this day forward,
you will govern
and command the six ministries.
I will not fail your trust.
I will do my utmost to guard the country
and await Your Majesty's triumphant return.
Your Majesty,
Yin Qing and the others
have infiltrated their old land in Qingzhou.
Beijian has troops at the border,
but they don't attack.
Yeqi's army is conducting a show of force
at Qingxia Pass.
Taishui's cavalry
raided our Jizhou camp by night,
burning three of our military granaries.
War broke out, and there is no time to lose.
Our soldiers will advance
in three directions.
Shen Zhi Shu,
lead your troops straight to Yeqi
and tell their king
to weigh whether to be our enemy or ally.
As you command.
Di Nian,
lead the elite troops directly to Taishui.
You must break through the city
within seven days.
I will not let you down!
Your Majesty, once the Second Prince's body
returns to his country,
Beijian will surely use this
as an excuse to attack.
Then our army will be attacked
front and rear.
We don't need to wait for Beijian to come.
In three days,
I will lead the campaign against Beijian.
I will let them know
that Ning Empire is not a place
they can attack at will.
I volunteer to be the vanguard.
Lord Xu was quite good to me.
I must avenge his death.
I will do it at any cost.
Good.
Soldiers, with powerful enemies around us,
a step back leads to the loss of land,
while a step forward
creates an unbeatable line of defense.
I will live or die together
with all the soldiers.
Defend our territory!
Protect our people!
Your Highness,
this is where you used to live as a child.
Do you remember?
I've seen it in my dreams.
Here are the spirit tablets
of the Zhongwan royals and loyal martyrs.
Every midnight, we can hear their weeping.
After Zhongwan fell,
this place was neglected by Ning Empire.
We secretly quartered here.
On the first night,
hearing voices drove many of our people mad.
Mr. Shangguan,
the clan chief has been expecting you.